<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantified self on Almost Surely...</title>
    <link>http://nimahejazi.org/blog/categories/quantified-self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantified self on Almost Surely...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nimahejazi.org/blog/categories/quantified-self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>quantified self with Fitbit, part 1</title>
      <link>http://nimahejazi.org/blog/post/quantified-self-fitbit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nimahejazi.org/blog/post/quantified-self-fitbit-1/</guid>
      <description>An interesting phenomenon that has appeared in recent years is the notion of &amp;ldquo;Quantified Self&amp;rdquo; - simply the idea that quantifying much of our daily activity can lead to insights about our behaviors, and that a more thorough knowledge of our own behavior can help us to be more mindful of our health and lifestyle choices. In a previous post, I explored (in a very rudimentary fashion) information about my genome, in the form of single nucleotide polymorphisms sequenced by 23andMe™.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snooping through my SNPs, part 1</title>
      <link>http://nimahejazi.org/blog/post/snooping-thru-my-snps-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nimahejazi.org/blog/post/snooping-thru-my-snps-1/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the growing trend of personal genomics has spawned its own industry, with several companies now offering to sequence the genomes of individuals, with some even providing health analytics and ancestry information. A couple years ago, I sent a sample of my own DNA (via saliva) to 23andMe, Inc.; this sample was then used to perform sequencing on single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in my genome &amp;ndash; and to provide me with a wealth of information about potential disease risks and ancestry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>